<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Jeroen Trimbach &#39;s posts - Jeroen Trimbach</title>
        <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/posts/</link>
        <description>All Jeroen Trimbach &#39;s posts | Jeroen Trimbach</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 11:07:52 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeroentrimbach.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Customize Azure Linux VMs with cloud-init</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2023/02/cloud-init-ado/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 11:07:52 &#43;0100</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2023/02/cloud-init-ado/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Cloud-init is a popular open-source tool that automates the initial setup of a cloud instance, such as an Azure Linux virtual machine (VM). It allows administrators to define custom configurations, such as users, disk layout, and network settings, that will be applied to the instance when it is first launched. This way, you can quickly and consistently provision new instances with your desired configurations, eliminating the need for manual setup and configuration. In this post, we will explore how to use cloud-init on Azure Linux VMs to configure your instances according to your needs.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Splatting parameters in PowerShell</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/07/powershell-parameter-splatting/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:44:04 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/07/powershell-parameter-splatting/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>My preferred way of passing in parameters in PowerShell!</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Create Azure Cost Management exports</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/06/azure-cost-management-exports/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 14:59:32 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/06/azure-cost-management-exports/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Lets dig into some of the ways we can export the monthly costs of the resources the we have deployed in Microsoft Azure.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Update Azure NSG security rules using Bicep</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/05/azure-update-nsg-rules-bicep/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:51:16 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/05/azure-update-nsg-rules-bicep/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In this post I will be explaining how you can utilize Bicep (an Infrastructure as Code (IaC) language) for creating and/or updating the security rules on a Network Security Group (NSG) in Microsoft Azure. I have also shared a script which can be used to export a deployment template based on the security rules configured on an existing NSG resource so that you can use that for further deployments.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Azure Boards: Planning work items in BULK!</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/05/azure-boards-bulk-planning/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:53:55 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/05/azure-boards-bulk-planning/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Planning work items in Azure Boards can be a tedious task. In this post I will be explaining how you can plan/create work items using Microsoft Excel. Using Excel you can easily add a large amount of items in an efficient manner.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Powerful PowerShell cmdlet Out-ConsoleGridView</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/04/powershell-out-consolegridview/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 15:26:39 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2022/04/powershell-out-consolegridview/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In this post I will be sharing the PowerShell cmdlet Out-ConsoleGridView which is part of the ConsoleGuiTools module. Which is in my opinion well worth it to have in your toolbox!</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Azure Bicep: An introduction on how to get started</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2021/08/azure-bicep-intro/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 19:41:50 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2021/08/azure-bicep-intro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In this post I will explain what Bicep is and how you can get start using it for deploying resources to Microsoft Azure.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Publish a PowerShell Module using Github Actions</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2021/07/powershell-module-ci/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 19:06:05 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2021/07/powershell-module-ci/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A step-by-step tutorial on how to create a PowerShell Module and publish it to the PSGallery by using GitHub Actions</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create a website using Hugo and GitHub Pages</title>
    <link>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2021/06/site-setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 16:03:42 &#43;0200</pubDate><guid>https://jeroentrimbach.com/2021/06/site-setup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A write-up/step-by-step tutorial of I have setup my site using Hugo (a static site generator written in Go) and hosted it on GitHub Pages. I will take you to the process from setting up your config, picking a theme and pushing the files to a git repository to host the site.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
